Mitch Bilensky

General tech enthusiast with an interest in cloud development and architecture, DevOps, and home automation. Has been working as a full stack developer since 2015 mostly within Java (Spring Boot) and JavaScript (React and Angular), with a primary focus on the cloud

Woodmount Dr Fredericton, NB E3A 2M4 (506) 461-0630 mitch.bilensky@gmail.com mitch.bilensky.ca

EXPERIENCE

Quantiphi, Fredericton —Architect

May 2022 - PRESENT

Accreon was acquired by Quantiphi and the existing scrum team continued and personal role expanded to add the role of Architect for the migration for an insurance provider web client from an on-prem to an AWS solution.

Accreon, Fredericton — Lead Developer

APRIL 2021 - May 2022

Lead a scrum team of developers contracted for planning, building, deploying, and maintaining a series of cloud services used to automate business operations performed by a leading electronic health record platform. Primarily use Java and React to deploy containerized solutions to replace manual workflows used for data cleanliness and mergers & acquisitions with systems automated wherever possible and allow putting the data in the hands of the end users wherever possible

Accreon, Fredericton—Full Stack Developer

APRIL 2015 - APRIL 2021

Worked within a team of developers consulting for a large electronic health record system for a nursing home software solution. Built various solutions within their monolith application primarily including a document generation, management, and eSignature solution for custom admission documents integrated with an eSignature vendor and a CRM solution for managing incoming clients and tracking their onboarding workflows.

EDUCATION

New Brunswick Community College, Fredericton — *IT: Programmer Analyst*

SEPT 2013 - JUNE 2015

Graduated from New Brunswick's community college program with honours including a co-op program

SKILLS

Java -- Spring (MVC, Boot, Data, etc.), JPA, Flowable, JUnit,

JavaScript -- React, Redux, TypeScript, Angular, Cypress, Jest

AWS -- CloudFormation, S3, CloudFront, DynamoDB, Cognito, IAM

DevOps -- Jenkins, Helm, ArgoCD, GitLab CI, Github Actions

Infrastructure as Code --AWS CloudFormation/SAM, Terraform

Tools -- Git, Docker, Maven, NPM

INTERESTS

3D Printing -- Designer and printer of 3D models both practical and useless

Vinyl Records -- Collector of albums by Rush, Grateful Dead, Yes, and others

Golf -- Regular duffer and member at local course

Hiking -- Search for local trails and new places for taking my dogs out for walks